{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\ngorblflur means fan belt\npixngorbl means ceiling fan\narthtusl means tile roof\nWhich word could mean \"ceiling tile\"?", "opta": "gorbltusl", "optb": "flurgorbl", "optc": "arthflur", "optd": "pixnarth", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Gorbl means fan; flur means belt; pixn means ceiling; arth means tile; and  tusl means roof. Therefore, pixnarth is the correct choice."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\nhapllesh means cloudburst\nsrenchoch means pinball\nresbosrench means ninepin\nWhich word could mean \"cloud nine\"?", "opta": "leshsrench", "optb": "ochhapl", "optc": "haploch", "optd": "haplresbo", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Hapl means cloud; lesh means burst; srench means pin;  och means ball; and  resbo means nine. Leshsrench (choice a) doesn't contain any of the words needed for cloud nine. We know that och means ball, so that rules out choices b and c. When you combine hapl (cloud) with resbo (nine), you  get the correct answer"}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\nagnoscrenia means poisonous spider\ndelanocrenia means poisonous snake\nagnosdeery means brown spider\nWhich word could mean \"black widow spider\"?", "opta": "deeryclostagnos", "optb": "agnosdelano", "optc": "agnosvitriblunin", "optd": "trymuttiagnos", "ans": "C", "explanation": "In this language, the noun appears first and the adjectives follow. Since agnos means spider and should appear first, choices a and d can be ruled out. Choice b can be ruled out because delano means snake."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\nmoolokarn means blue sky\nwilkospadi means bicycle race\nmoolowilko means blue bicycle\nWhich word could mean \"racecar\"?", "opta": "wilkozwet", "optb": "spadiwilko", "optc": "moolobreil", "optd": "spadivolo", "ans": "D", "explanation": "From wilkospadi, you can determine that wilko means bicicyle and spadi means race. Therefore, the first part of the word that means racecar should begin with spadi. That limits your choices to b and d. Choice b, spadiwilko, is incorrect because we have already determined that wilkomeans bicycle. Therefore, the answer must be choice d, spadivolo."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\nmigenlasan means cupboard\nlasanpoen means boardwalk\ncuopdansa means pullman\nWhich word could mean \"walkway\"?", "opta": "poenmigen", "optb": "cuopeisel", "optc": "lasandansa", "optd": "poenforc", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Migen means cup; lasan means board; poen means walk; cuop means pull; and dansa means man. The only possible choices, then, are choices a and d. Choice a can be ruled out because migen means cup."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\ngodabim means kidney stones\nromzbim means kidney beans\nromzbako means wax beans\nWhich word could mean \"wax statue\"?", "opta": "godaromz", "optb": "lazbim", "optc": "wasibako", "optd": "romzpeo", "ans": "C", "explanation": "In this language, the adjective follows the noun. From  godabim and  romzbim, you can determine that bim means kidney. From  romzbim and  romzbako, you can determine that  romz means beans. Therefore, bako  means wax. Because the adjective wax must come after the noun in this language, wasibako is the only choice."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\ngranamelke means big tree\npinimelke means little tree\nmelkehoon means tree house\nWhich word could mean \"big house\"?", "opta": "granahoon", "optb": "pinishur", "optc": "pinihoon", "optd": "melkegrana", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Grana means big;melkemeans tree; pini means little; hoonmeans house. Therefore, granahoon means big house."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\ndaftafoni means advisement\nimodafta means misadvise\nimolokti means misconduct\nWhich word could mean \"statement\"?", "opta": "kratafoni", "optb": "kratadafta", "optc": "loktifoni", "optd": "daftaimo", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Dafta means advise; foni is the same as the suffix -ment; imo is the same as the prefix mis-; lokti means conduct. Since the only word in the answer choices that hasn't been defined is  krata, it is reasonable to assume that krata means state. Therefore, kratafoni is the only choice that could mean statement."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\nlelibroon means yellow hat\nplekafroti means flower garden\nfrotimix means garden salad\nWhich word could mean \"yellow flower\"?", "opta": "lelifroti", "optb": "lelipleka", "optc": "plekabroon", "optd": "frotibroon", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Leli means yellow; broon means hat; pleka means flower; froti means garden; mix means salad. Therefore, lelipleka means yellow flower."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\nmyncabel means saddle horse\nconowir means trail ride\ncabelalma means horse blanket\nWhich word could mean \"horse ride\"?", "opta": "cabelwir", "optb": "conocabel", "optc": "almamyn", "optd": "conoalma", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Myn means saddle; cabel means horse; cono means trail; and wir means ride. Therefore, cabelwir is the correct answer."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\ndionot means oak tree\nblyonot means oak leaf\nblycrin means maple leaf\nWhich word could mean \"maple syrup\"?", "opta": "blymuth", "optb": "hupponot", "optc": "patricrin", "optd": "crinweel", "ans": "C", "explanation": "In this language, the adjective follows the noun. From dionot and blyonot, you can determine that 'onot' means oak. From blyonot and blycrin, you can determine that bly means leaf. Therefore, crin means maple. Because the adjective maple comes after the noun, patricrin is the only possible choice."}, {"question": "Here are some words translated from an artificial language.\ntamceno means sky blue\ncenorax means blue cheese\naplmitl means star bright\nWhich word could mean \"bright sky\"?", "opta": "cenotam", "optb": "mitltam", "optc": "raxmitl", "optd": "aplceno", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Tam means sky; ceno means blue; rax means cheese; apl means star; and mitl means bright. So, mitltam means bright sky."}]]}